Guide to the Elizabeth Barlow Rogers Papers 1906-2020 (bulk 1960s-2010s) MS 3206
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Written Works and Materials, 1962-2020
  - Subseries I.A Drafts and Research, 1962-2020
    - Correspondence With Editor Julia Moore, 1998-2000 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence With Yale University Press for Landscape Design, 1991-2007 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence From Outside Readers of Landscape Design, 1995-2000 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence For Illustrations and Designs of Landscape Design, 1995-2000 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence From Outside Readers of Landscape Design, 1997-2000 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence From Readers After Publication of Landscape Design, 1999-2002 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence With Publishers For Final Draft of Landscape Design, 2000-2001 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 13)
    - Abrams Contract for Landscape Design, 1997-1998 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence With Editors and Readers for Landscape Design, 1999-2000 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 22)
    - Landscape Design Drafts with Comments (10 folders), 1992-1994 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 23-32)
    - Correspondence from Bard Graduate Center; Letters from Academic Advisors at Inception, 2000-2001 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence Regarding EBR Article in Viewpoints, 2004-2005 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with Forests and Wetlands Editor Julian Bach, 1970-1972 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence for Frederick Law Olmsted's New York, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 14)
    - Landscape Design Forward Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 1)
    - Landscape Design Introduction Peer Review and Research, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 2)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 1 Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 3)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 1, Frontmatter, Notes with Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 4)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 1 Peer Review, 1998 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 5)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 1 Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 6)
    - Landscape Design Chapters 1-2 Peer Review, Letters, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 7)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 2 Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 8)
    - Landscape Design Chapters 2-3 Captions, Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 9)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 3 Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 10)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 3 Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 11)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 3 Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 12)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 3 Captions, Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 13)
    - Landscape Design Frontmatter, Chapter 3 Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 14)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 4 Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 15)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 4 Captions, Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 16)
    - Landscape Design Chapters 4-5 Captions, Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 17)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 5 Peer Review, 1998 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 18)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 5 Captions, Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 19)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 6 Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 20)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 6 Captions, Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 21)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 6 Captions, Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 22)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 7 Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 23)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 7 Captions, Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 24)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 7 Captions, Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 25)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 8 Peer Review, 1998 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 26)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 8 Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 27)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 8 Captions, Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 28)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 8 Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 29)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 8 Captions, Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 30)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 9 Draft, 1998 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 31)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 9 Peer Review, 1998 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 32)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 9 Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 33)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 9 Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 34)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 9 Captions, Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 35)
    - Landscape Design Chapters 9-10 Editor's Queries, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 36)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 10 Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 37)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 10 Peer Review, Notes, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 38)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 10 Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 39)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 10 Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 40)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 11 Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 41)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 12 Peer Review, 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 42)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 14 Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 43)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 14 Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 44)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 14 Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 45)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 14 Captions, Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 46)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 15 Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 47)
    - Landscape Design Chapter 15 Captions, Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 48)
    - Landscape Design Bibliography Peer Review, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 49)
    - Landscape Design Comments, Correspondence From Julia Moore and Reuben Rainey, 2000 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 50)
    - Personal Journal, 1989-1990 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1)
    - Essays, 2001 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 2)
    - Poetry, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 3)
    - Garden Columns, circa 1970 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 6)
    - I.M. Pei Article, 1977 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 7)
    - "English Gardens" Film, Prints, and Manuscripts, 1974 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 16)
    - Article on the American West, undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 17)
    - Tidewater Hudson, circa 1973 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 20)
    - Sissinghurst - Vita Sackville West, 1974 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 21)
    - Teddy Blue (cowboy), 1975 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 22)
    - The Annotated Diary of Eliza Bellamy, circa 1970 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 25)
    - English Gardens Notebook, undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 26)
  - Subseries I.B Press and Reviews, 1969-2018
    Subseries I.B Press and Reviews (1969-2018) includes clippings, promotional materials, and reviews that Rogers received by mail from readers. The Subseries contains materials for numerous titles represented in Series I, although there are some press materials for manuscripts which are not found in the collection. The Subseries also contains strategy documents and correspondence from publishers and associates of Rogers who helped promote her work.
    Materials in Subseries I.B are organized by project in roughly the order that they were published.
    - The Forests and Wetlands of New York City National Book Award, 1972 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
    - Reviews and Publicity, circa 1970s (Offsite-box 6, Folder 6)
    - Forests and Wetlands Clippings and Correspondence, 1971-1975 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 7)
    - Forests and Wetlands Promotional Materials, 1971 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 8)
    - Letters on Forests and Wetlands at Time of Publication, 1970-1971 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 9)
    - Forests and Wetlands Outline and Promotional Correspondence, 1969 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 10)
    - Publicity Suggestions for Forests and Wetlands, 1971 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 11)
    - Complimentary Reviews and Correspondence for Forests and Wetlands, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 12)
    - Clippings and Reviews of Frederick Law Olmsted's New York, 1972-1983 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 15)
    - Letters on East Hampton: A History and Guide at Publication, 1975 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 16)
    - Clippings and Reviews from East Hampton: A History and Guide, 1975 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 17)
    - Press and Clippings from Landscape Design (1 of 3), 1998-2004 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 18)
    - Press and Clippings from Landscape Design (2 of 3), 2001-2005 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 19)
    - Press and Clippings from Landscape Design (3 of 3), 2002 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 20)
    - Press and Clippings from Learning Las Vegas, 2013 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 21)
    - Press for Green Metropolis, 2016 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 22)
    - Recorded Talk and Clippings from Writing the Garden (1 of 2), 2011-2012 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 23)
      Includes one CD-R with recording of EBR's talk on Writing the Garden. Digital access files were created 4/20/2022.
      Conditions Governing Access
      The discs were retained for context, but the files on the discs may not be accessed. Patrons may only use the preserved digital files from the CD listed above.
    - Recorded Talk on Writing the Garden (2 of 2) Digital Files, 2011 (Digital file MS 3206)
      Digital files can be made available online for viewing only. To arrange to receive a link to the desired digital files, contact reference@nyhistory.org.
    - Clippings and Promotional Materials for Saving Central Park, 2018 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 24)
    - Forests and Wetlands Publicity, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 8)
    - Reviews of Forests and Wetlands, 1971-1974 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 18)
    - John Burroughs Medal, 1973 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 19)
    - East Hampton: A History and Guide Reviews and Letters, 1975 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 24)
- Series II. Professional Papers and Central Park Conservancy Records, 1962-2019
  Series II contains materials related to Elizabeth Barlow Rogers' career in parks advocacy and administration, as well as her professional and social engagements that stemmed from her prominent role in New York City municipal and civic life. The bulk of her professional work documented here pertains to her job as Central Park administrator from 1979-1995 and her role as founder and President of the Central Park Conservancy from 1980-1995. In addition, her early advocacy for environmental conservation, urban development, and her later restoration efforts nationally and abroad are also documented here.
  Series II Consists of the following four subseries:
  Subseries II.A Official Publications, 1973-2015
  Subseries II.B Publicity and Correspondence, 1971-2019
  Subseries II.C Advocacy, 1962-2019
  Subseries II.D Graphic Materials and Audiovisual Materials, 1968-2011
  - Subseries II.A Official Publications, 1973-2015
    This subseries consists of printed matter that document the activities of the Central Park Conservancy. Published reports, brochures, advertising materials, and scripts make up the bulk of the subseries. The materials range widely in date, but are clustered around Rogers' activities in the 1970-1980s and the 1990s-2010s. While Rogers retired from the CPC and Parks Department in 1995, she is a lifelong trustee and continued her active public life in parks and urban arenas.
    Materials in this subseries are arranged in the original order that they were received from the donor.
    - The Symposium - Central Park (Japanese Language), DVD of Event (1 of 2), circa 2012 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 9)
      A digital access copy of the DVD was created 4/20/2022.
      The discs were retained for context, but the files on the discs may not be accessed. Patrons may only use the preserved digital files from the DVD listed above.
    - The Symposium - Central Park (Japanese Language), DVD of Event (2 of 2) Digital File, circa 2012 (Digital file MS 3206)
    - The Wonder of New York Campaign, 1994 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 14)
    - Central Park Conservancy Trustee Handbook, 2015 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 15)
    - The Central Park Effect (report), 2015 November (Offsite-box 8, Folder 16)
    - CPC Outline for Restoration Plan (report), 1980-1981 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 18)
    - Central Park Conservancy Annual Reports (2 folders), 1985-2000 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 19-20)
    - New York City Parks and Recreation Department Annual Reports, 1983-1986 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 21)
    - Central Park Brochures and CPC Event Invitations, 1967-1987 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 1)
    - Wild Wild World of Animals TV Scripts, 1974 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 7)
    - Seeing Central Park (Documentary) Script, circa 1973 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 8)
    - Central Park Taskforce (3 folders), 1973-1984 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 12-14)
  - Subseries II.B Publicity and Correspondence, 1971-2019
    This subseries is made up of clippings, interviews, and other publicity documents relating to Rogers' work as CPC member and Central Park administrator. It also contains files maintained by Rogers on related projects and parks/urban renewal efforts in American cities and abroad. Within are correspondence and other research materials related to her collaborations in an official capacity. There is also correspondence and printed matter from relationships that were both professional and personal, such as her friendship with Brooke Astor. The bulk of this subseries is from the late 1980s to the mid 2010s.
    Materials are arranged in their original order. The materials in Box 15 were part of an earlier gift from Rogers in 2008 and were physically arranged but not described at that time. Almost all of these materials were integrated into Subseries II.B but select folders can be found elsewhere in the finding aid.
    - Printed Ephemera From Brooke Astor's Birthday, 1992 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 1)
    - Clippings of EBR's Work in the Parks Department, 1982-2002 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 2)
    - Clippings of Urban Studies Articles, 2017-2019 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 4)
    - EBR Interview on the Highline, 2015 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 6)
    - Guestbook from Spring Engagements, 2002 February-2003 May (Offsite-box 8, Folder 7)
    - Publicity Correspondence, 1983-1987 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 8)
    - EBR and Central Park Articles and Press (2 folders), 1980-2016 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 10-11)
    - EBR and Central Park Clippings (2 folders), 1979-2003 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 12-13)
    - Clippings on Central Park History, 1974-1995 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 17)
    - EBR Professional and Civil Activities Clippings (11 folders), 1970-2019 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 1-11)
    - Careers in Conservation (monograph), 1980 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 12)
    - Clippings from EBR's Retirement as Central Park Administrator and Central Park Conservancy President, 1995 December 31 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 13)
    - Speaking Engagements, 1997-2004 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 14)
    - Fred Wiseman Correspondence Re: Central Park Documentary, 1988-1990 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1)
    - Cityscape Institute Correspondence Files A-Z (16 folders), 1995-1999 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 2-17)
    - Central Park Conservancy Resignation Correspondence, 1991-1999 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 18)
    - Cityscape Street Furniture, 1992-2000 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence on EBR's Proposed Book, 1991-1996 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 20)
    - ABC: Exploring the Park Correspondence, 1989 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 21)
    - European Parks Correspondence, 1989-1991 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 22)
    - CPC Letters and Ephemera, 1991-1995 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 23)
    - EBR Park Correspondence with National Organizations, 1991-1994 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 24)
    - Publicity and Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 25)
    - Public Space for Public Life Project Correspondence (2 folders), 1991-1992 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 26-27)
    - CPC and Central Park Administrator Correspondence (3 folders), 1978-2002 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 28-30)
    - Book Subvention Correspondence, 1999-2002 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 31)
    - Bard Graduate Center Posters and Flyers, 2002-2003 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 32)
    - Bard Graduate Center Director Correspondence, 2001-2003 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 33)
    - Events Correspondence for CPC, Central Park Administration, 1984-1994 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous Social Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous Central Park Correspondence, 1973-1998 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 36)
    - Civil Society Correspondence, Friends, 1991-1996 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 37)
      File includes, among other things, letters from Yoko Ono, Ivana Trump, Ed Koch
    - Park Enhancement District and Battery Park Correspondence, 1995 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence with Other Central Park Authors, 1997 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 39)
    - Brooklyn Bridge Park Correspondence, 2000 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 40)
    - Randall's Island Sports Foundation Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 41)
    - Bloomberg For Mayor Re: Parks Correspondence, 2001 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence with New York Figures Re: Urban Improvement, 1995-2001 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 43)
    - City Parks Foundation and Mary McCormick (Fund for the City of New York) Correspondence (2 folders), 1994-1997 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 44-45)
    - Cityscape Institute Correspondence, 1995-2000 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 47)
    - Barcelona-New York Urban Dialogue Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 48)
    - Lambert Pohner Letters and Illustrations, 1982-1983 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 4)
    - Central Park Journal and Correspondence, 1979-1983 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 5)
    - Browning Family Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 22)
    - National Park Foundation, 1994 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 1)
    - Cornell University, 1990 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 2)
    - "Post 2000" Parks Correspondence, 1995-2001 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 3)
    - Piedmont Park Conservancy, 1989-1991 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 4)
    - Weequahic Park Association, 1993-2000 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 5)
    - Buffalo Olmsted Parks Conservancy, 1993-1996 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 6)
    - "Pre 2001" CPC Correspondence, 1990-1998 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 7)
    - Forest Park, St. Louis, Missouri, 1990-1993 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 9)
    - Boston Parks, 1986-1995 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 10)
    - French Colleagues, 1989-1991 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 11)
    - Versailles Restoration, 1991 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 12)
    - Dayton, Ohio, 1993-1994 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 13)
    - Cincinnati, Ohio, 1995 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 14)
    - New Orleans Parkway and Parks Commission, 1992 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 15)
    - Chicago, Illinois, 1989-2000 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 16)
    - Houston, Texas, 1990-1995 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 17)
    - Fort Worth, Texas, 2000 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 18)
    - Asian Colleagues, 1990-1998 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 19)
    - Hyde Park, Australia, 1989-1992 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 20)
    - The Spanish Institute, Barcelona, 1994-1995 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Professional Correspondence Outside New York City, 1995-1997 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 22)
  - Subseries II.C Advocacy, 1962-2019
    Rogers began her career in parks administration as a research aide for Whitney North Seymour Jr., a New York State Senator from 1966-1968. Seymour was a founding member of the Natural Resources Defense Council (NRDC). The bulk of the advocacy papers are focused on her work for Seymour, particularly around the expansion of bike paths and trails and the preservation of waterways in New York State. Another collection of papers within this subseries pertains to the 1970s activism of civic groups in response to the fiscal crisis and perceived decay of New York City. Her later advocacy related directly to her work in the CPC, particularly urban planning and renewal.
    The subseries is generally arranged in the original order it was received in. Some oversized materials were separated and are linked in the finding aid.
    - Bike Trails, Conservation Advocacy (1 of 2), 1968 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 28)
      See corresponding oversized material in Box 16 Folder 1.
    - Bike Trails, Conservation Advocacy (2 of 2), 1968 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 1)
      See corresponding material in Box 6 Folder 28.
    - Garden Tours Printed Ephemera, 2007-2019 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 3)
    - Foundation For Landscape Studies Tour Materials, 2005-2007 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 5)
    - Rebuilding Central Park Notes and Slides, 2001 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 23)
    - Seymour Legislation, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 1)
    - Public Space for Public Life, 1993 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 2)
    - Park Association of New York City Speeches and Reports, 1966-1968 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 3)
    - Trails and Bikeways Advocacy (2 folders), 1965-1968 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 4-5)
    - Waterways and Wetlands Advocacy, 1964-1968 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 6)
    - Articles on the Environment, 1970-1971 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 9)
    - Parks Association of NYC Articles and Related Press, 1968-1976 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 10)
    - Clippings on Urban Planning, Lindsay Administration, 1969-1991 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 11)
    - Articles By Others on City Planning Issues, undated (Offsite-box 10, Folder 12)
    - Park Association Budget and Planning Committee, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 13)
    - Essays and Clippings on Urban Improvement, 1971-1973 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 14)
    - Municipal Art Society, 1967-1974 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 15)
    - Toward a Quieter City (report), 1970 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 16)
    - Conservation Projects and Civil Advocacy, 1967-1970 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 18)
    - Clippings and Reflections on Landscape History, 1967-1970 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 19)
    - Whitney North Seymour, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 20)
    - Conservation - Regional, 1967-1979 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 21)
    - Conservation and Environment Clippings, 1969-1977 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 22)
    - NY Transportation Memo to Roger Starr, circa 1962 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 23)
    - Robert Moses Article Re: Biography, 1974 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 24)
    - Speeches on the Environment, circa 1970 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 25)
    - State Park Commission for NYC, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 26)
    - Research on Environmental Health and Urban Planning, 1968 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous Photos and Research on NYC Environment, 1966-1974 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 28)
    - Institute for Urban Design Conference, Proposals, 1994-1995 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 46)
    - Speeches on Central Park, 1983 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 10)
    - Forest Park, St. Louis, R/UDAT, 1976 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 15)
  - Subseries II.D Graphic Materials and Audiovisual Materials, 1968-2011
    The subseries includes photographs, illustrations, and graphics related to Rogers' public life and professional work as well as photographs and audiovisual materials focusing on Central Park itself. There are also several recorded lectures and interviews given by Rogers to news stations and civic groups. Audiovisual materials are listed in the finding aid along with their digitization status. Some photographs of Central Park were taken by prominent photographers such as Bruce Davidson and Ruth Orkin. Rogers appears photographed with various important figures such as Barbara and George H.W. Bush, Ed Koch, Rudy Giuliani, and Brooke Astor.
    - Optical Media from Central Park Conservatory (CPC) (1 of 2), 2005-2009 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 25)
      Two DVD-Rs and one CD-R. The DVD-Rs are interviews with EBR produced by Chelsea Studios, Inc. for the CPC. The CD-R is a "QM2 Lecture" probably given by EBR as a guest of Oxford University during a cruise. Digital access files were created 4/20/2022.
      The discs were retained for context, but the files on the discs may not be accessed. Patrons may only use the preserved digital files from the CDs listed above.